MICHAEL BUBB

Phone: +1.201.736.0870

Email: michael.bubb@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mpbubb

GitHub: github.com/mbubb

gpgKey: mbubb.devio.us/gpg/pub_key.asc

PROFILE

Linux Systems Engineer

With over a decade of root access on enterprise Linux environments, I have managed datacenter buildouts as well as cloud infrastructure (mostly GCE). Often starting in a 'sole systems role', I have built and lead teams as organizations have gone through rapid growth. Current focuses include: CI/CD with Github, Ansible and Jenkins; Prometheus monitoring deployments.

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Senior Systems Engineer | May 2015 - present

Forensig New York, NY. (Impact Radius as of July 2016)

- SRE for 350 servers in multiple global datacenters (98% CentOS 6.x)
- Infrastructure management (DNS, System and Network Monitoring)
- Build/Deploy with Ansible-Jenkins-Github
- Ansible project lead/ Jenkins admin
- deployments to Google Cloud and AWS

Systems Engineer | August 2014 - May 2015

OnDeck New York, NY.

- Linux System Administration (CentOS and Ubuntu)
- Ansible configuration
- Postgresql support

Operations Engineer | June 2010 - August 2014

Collective New York, NY.

- General Linux System Administration CentOS and Ubuntu
- Datacenter management
- Hadoop buildout and support
- Netezza administration
- Automation Cobbler; Puppet; Razor; Ansible
- DNS administration
- Bash and Python scripting
- git and github code management
- monitoring with Nagios; Boundary; Circonus; Catchpoint

Systems Administrator | 2006 – 2010

Shipco Hoboken, NJ.

- Linux and UNIX System Administration
- Debian Firewall and Samba installation and configuration
- backup management on 75 servers
- Basic configuration and setup Cisco 26xx routers and HP Procurve 25xx switches
- Organized and carried out Datacenter move of all company servers
- Datacenter management
- Responsible for purchasing and billing authorization
- Help Desk Management for a 700 employee, 50 office global company

Junior System Administrator | 2005 – 2006

Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, NJ.

While enrolled at Stevens in Computer Science I worked as a UNIX System Administrator in the NetBSD Computer lab as well as on a Beowulf Cluster.

Network and Systems Administration (independent consultant) | 2000 - 2005

- Setup networks and practice management systems for lawfirms and veterinary clinics in NYC and Northern NJ.
- Handled legal discovery/ litigation management for lawfirms.
- website hosting on a RedHat server at Datapipe.

EDUCATION

Degree

- BA English, minor in Political Science from **Rutgers University, New Bruswick** (1992).

Non-matriculated

- 40 credits Computer Science, **Stevens Institute of Technology**, Hoboken, NJ (2005-2006).
- 48 credits Comparative Literature, PhD program, NYU, New York, NY (1993-1995).

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

- 2016 | licensed EMR, ambulance driver Hoboken Volunteer Ambulance
- 2014-present | middle school volunteer teacher (Scratch, Python), Elysian Charter School
- 2013-2015 | technical volunteer, **Milemesh**.
- 2012-present | emergency shelter and communications, Hoboken CERT.
- 2004-2006 | webmaster; editor, **NonServiam Press**.
- 1999-2004 | webmaster; editor, The Brooklyn Rail.
- 1995–1999 | curriculum dev; teaching manager **Berlitz Korea** Seoul, Korea.
- 1989-1991 | prep cook; garde manger, Frog and the Peach.